

HUSSEIN MAKKI

ABOUT ME

A Well-Established Media Expert with three years of experience in various global & regional entities. I managed to help them grow through my talents in Communications, Voice Acting, TV, Social Media & Radio Presenting, Photography, editing and many more fields of expertise that I acquired over the years through my professional & volunteer experiences.

CONTACT

Address:
Nasr Road, Nasr City, Cairo, Egypt
Phone:

+2011 252 66 240

Email: Husseiny.makki@gmail.com

REFERENCE

PATIENT ATCHO

Communications Officer, AU Commission Phone: +251 929335250 Email: atchop@africa-union.org

MOHANED MEGAHED

Business Solution Manager, ICT Trust Fund Phone: +20100 6319573 Email: mmegahed@mcit.gov.eg

EDUCATION

Cairo University

FACULTY OF ECONOMICS & POLITICAL SCIENCE

2011 - 2016

- English Section
- Major in Political Science
- Minor in Statistics

AB Language School

GENERAL SECONDARY EDUCATION

2009 - 2011

- Grade Score: 96%
- Courses: Biology, Chemistry, Math, English, German, Arabic, Statistics, Economics, Physics & A-Level

EXPERIENCE

Video Editor

EFAF - EGYPTIAN FEDERATION, AMERICAN FOOTBALL

October 2018 - Ongoing

- Create appealing videos based on the required campaigns
- Take the required footage myself when needed
- Directing & Producing the whole Video from A to Z

Co-Star

CGTN'S REALITY SHOW "HI CHINA!"

June 2018 - July 2018

- Co-Starred a Television Reality Series called Hi China that will Air officially on CGTN late August/Early September 2018.
- Filmed episodes in the Traditional Medicine City of Qichun, visited Huaxi Village the richest village in China and also Inner Mongolia.

Radio Presenter

FM HAWA

Feb. 2018 - April. 2018

- Radio Presenter & Content Creator at FM Hawa for my own show "Basy w shoot" (Pass & Shoot)
- Delivered an online radio show about Sports and everything about it; Soccer, Female & Sports, the Psychology of Sports and more!
- Had a lot of Special Guests including:
- . Afaf Al-Hodhod, Egypt's Olympic shooting Player, Africa's #1, World Rank #6 & Mediterranean Games 2018 Medalist.
- . Dr. Hossam Hassan Gadou, Sports Expert
- . Muhammad Zizzu, Social Media Sports Sensation.
- . Karim Mohamed, Radio Sports Presenter.

Voice Actor

FREELANCER

2016 - ongoing

- Record & Produce Voice Overs for Commercials, Presentations, Narrations, IVRs, Educational Material and Videos.
- Have clients in over 6 countries from 4 different continents.
- Clients include Governments, Individuals & famous Brands

Communications Associate

AFRICAN UNION COMMISSION

August 2017 - Oct. 2017

- Communications Associate, At the Contiinental Free Trade Area Unit at the Department of Trade & Industry, Addis Ababa Ethiopia.
- One of the main Designers, Photographers & Video-Editors for the department of Department of Trade and Industry.
- Handle Twitter & Facebook pages for the Department of Trade and Industry at the African Union Commission.

Project Assistant

UNDP

October 2016 - Feb. 2017

- A short term project assisting Ambassador Wafaa Bassim in evaluating and monitoring the performance of the Cairo Center for Conflict Resolution and Peacekeeping in Africa (CCCPA).
- Conducted Interviews with Staff members, Japanese Ambassador to Egypt & other engaged Stakeholders.
- Made required Statistics, Researches & papers needed for the proper conduction of the Evaluation.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Organizer

MINISTRY OF YOUTH & SPORTS

2014 - 2018

- Participated in organizing Presidential, Sports & high-level events.
- Arabic-English Translator in multiple events.
- Live Translator at the Press conference of the ITKF World Cup 2014
- Part of the Organizing Team of the Presidential Tent in the New Suez Canal Inauguration.
- Assistant to the Secretary General of the UIPM Ms. Shiny Fang in 20014 & 2015.
- Assistant & Translator of the President of the International Traditional Karate Federation during the World Cup in 2014.

Multiple Positions

AIESEC

2012 - 2014

- Internal Auditor AIESEC in Ain Shams University
- National Support Board, Internal

Commuincation - AIESEC Egypt Jan-June 2014

- Global Societal Program Manager AIESEC Cairo University 2013/14.
- Cultural Envoy for Exchange Development AIESEC Italy Feb-March 2014
- Organizing Committee President, Interns Conference - AIESEC Egypt 2012
- Exchange Participant AIESEC Campinas, Brazil from Jan-March 2012
- Facilitated Multiple Conferences, Chaired Elections and hosted a RnR Event

Team Leader Announcers team

MEN'S AFRICAN VOLLEYBALL CHAMPIONSHIP

October 2017

- Led a team of 6 announcers throughout the Championship
- Coach, mentor and guide them on how to publicly announce pre, during and after matches.
- Provided the necessary training & coaching related to the field of work.

Editor in Chief

THE INSIDER FEPS

Dec 2013 - Jan 2014

- Full management over the Insider's different social media platofmrs.
- Coordinate and synergize different teams to reach out successful media coverage for college news and events.
- Held the final approval for any post or pieces of news prior to its release.

SKILLS

SOFTWARES

LANGUAGES

Communication
Leadership
Creative Writing
Presentation
Social Media Knowledge
Team Work
Time Management
Problem Solving

Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Audition
Final Cut Pro
VideoScribe
Microsoft Powerpoint

Arabic - Native English - Fluent German - Basic